Darshil Kapadia

darshilkapadia9@gmail.com (+91)98797-23000 Salabatpura, Surat, Gujarat, India.395003

To proceed along the path which I took upon 4 years ago and creating a career in the same by contributing in the fields like Artificial Intelligence and Data Science. To seek education from San Jose State University and in the process boosting my intelligence to help me pursue my dream of becoming a Software Developer and Data Scientist.

Education

Sarvajanik College of Engg. and Tech, Surat

July, 2013-June, 2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering CGPA: 9.15

Experience

R.K. Infratel, Surat

May 2017 - July 2017

Intern, Developer

Smart- Pole System

- -Lead the 4 person team on the project.
- -Created a Restful API to communicate with our Smart-Pole Web Service.
- -Smart-Pole Web Service helps user monitor the data collected from various sensors like Temperature sensor, Vibration sensor (to detect earthquakes) etc.
- -Data Visualization of data of various sensors on the web service using Heat-Maps, Charts, History, Line Graphs using Google-Maps API.
- -Smart-Pole Web Service authenticates a user using web tokens for user to use our services.

Deep Technologies, Surat

November 2017 - May 2018

Intern, Developer

Web Development

- Used HTML, CSS for web design
- Used JavaScript, PHP, MySQL as back-end technologies.

Projects

Home On Phone(HOP)

June, 2016 - June, 2017

Final Year Project

The goal of this project was to encourage the government's initiative to make the city smarter. This project includes some very useful features which can be used in day to day life and which were selected after observing the difficulties that we face in our daily life. Along with making the homes smarter, this project also focuses on conserving the energy viz. Electrical Energy. Another remarkable thing was that the investment needed to bring the control of your home to the phone was made very cheaper with this project.

This project includes various features/modules which focuses on areas like Enhanced Security, Energy Conservation, Easy control to home appliances etc. These features are divided into various modules like

Module 1: Security Through Geo-FencingModule 2: Light Watch

Module 3: Ambience Assistant Module 4: Mail-Box Notifier

Web Data Management

December, 2016 – June, 2017

4th Year

Created a Big-Data related program to find the most occurring word/s in a given data using Hadoop in a Linux environment. Used HDFS and Map-Reduce algorithm.

Mobile Computing

July, 2016 - December, 2016

4th Year

Created an Android Weather Application in Android Studio environment that fetches weather of 7 days from "openweatherapi".

Information And Network Security

July, 2016 - December, 2016

4th Year

Implemented password encryption application using RSA encryption algorithm.

Analysis and Design of Algorithm

July, 2015 - December, 2016

3rd Year

Created a simple and most popular feature i.e Find and Replace feature using a string matching algorithm Knuthh-Morris-Pratt.

Awards And Participations

- -Secured 1st position at the Project Showcase Competition held by Computer Society of India, 2017.
- -Participated in International Experience Program (IEP) hosted by Laurentian University, Canada.
- -Participated in Reform'n'ation A Challenge to lead India by Techfest, IIT Bombay.
- -Attended Ethical Hacking Expert (integrated level 1.0 & 2.0) workshop at Nirma University, Ahmedabad.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- -Event head of Vernissage Program held by SCET in Co-Updates 2014.
- -Student- Coordinator in Paper Presentation event during Kshitij 2015.
- -Participated in CO-Olympics for 4 years and ended Runners Up in Cricket in the 2017.
- -Took part in Dance Performance during CO-Creo, 2015.
- -Organized and Hosted a Farewell Party, 2016.

Technical Skills

Operating Systems:

All Windows environment, Unix/Linux, CentOS, Android, Raspbian.

Scripting Language:

Shell, JavaScript, PHP.

Frameworks:

JSF, Hibernate, SpringMVC.

Databases:

MongoDB, MariaDB, SqlDB.

Programming Languages:

C, C++, PL/SQL, x85 Assembly, Java, Prolog, Python, Lua.

Web Technologies:

HTML, XHTML, JSP, CSS, XML